Guide to the Secular Yiddish Schools in North America Collection M0732
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
- Series 4. Accession 2011-166
  - Lendlema, Sholem 1999 (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Lerner, Harold, Dr. 1997 (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Levine, Celia 1994 (Box 7, Folder 16)
  - Levine, Mark 1994 (Box 7, Folder 17)
  - Levine, Merke 1994 (Box 7, Folder 18)
  - Levinkind, Susan 1996 (Box 7, Folder 19)
  - Lewin, Noah 1998 (Box 7, Folder 20)
  - Lewin, Stanley 1998 (Box 7, Folder 21)
  - Linder, Irene 1996 (Box 7, Folder 22)
  - Lipshitz, Leonard & Melina 1992 (Box 7, Folder 23)
  - Lustig, Joel 1996 (Box 7, Folder 24)
  - Lynn Florette 1997 (Box 7, Folder 25)
  - Majsner, Luke 1993 (Box 7, Folder 26)
  - Makofsky, Abraham 1997 (Box 7, Folder 27)
  - Malamed, Daniyel & Riva 1992 (Box 7, Folder 28)
  - Maranz, Steven 1997 (Box 7, Folder 29)
  - Mark, Harry/Hershc 1995 (Box 7, Folder 30)
  - May, Bea Goldman 1992 (Box 7, Folder 31)
  - Maymudes, August L. 1996 (Box 7, Folder 32)
  - Meistrich, Gertrude/ GITL 1992 (Box 7, Folder 33)
  - Meckler, Ron 2001 (Box 7, Folder 34)
  - Melnick, Channe R. 1997 (Box 7, Folder 35)
  - Melrood, Laurie 1997 (Box 7, Folder 36)
  - Mehzer, Rae 1997 (Box 7, Folder 37)
  - Merdler, Lyle (Box 7, Folder 38)
  - Messigner, Miriam & Seymour (Box 7, Folder 39)
  - Metzger, Michel (Box 7, Folder 40)
  - Milbauer, Blanche (Box 7, Folder 41)
  - Miller, Alfred A. (Box 7, Folder 42)
  - Minkin, Cynthia Spielberg (Box 7, Folder 43)
  - Mintus, Helen Agin (Box 7, Folder 44)
  - Mitchner, Adele (Box 7, Folder 45)
  - Mlotek, Yosl (Box 7, Folder 46)
  - Mlotek, Zalmen (Box 7, Folder 47)
  - Monet, Rubye (Box 7, Folder 48)
  - Moskowitz, May (Box 7, Folder 49)
  - Moss, Ken (Box 7, Folder 50)
  - Myerson, Bess (Box 7, Folder 51)
  - Olitsky, Mattis (Box 7, Folder 52)
  - Olsen, Laurie (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Opatoshu, David (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Panush, Irving (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Palevsky, Simon (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Palevsky, Elliott (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Paul, Annette (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Peizer, Ruth (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Peretz, Martin (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Perlstein, H + M (Box 7, Folder 61)
  - Pinkson, Ruth (Box 7, Folder 62)
  - Portnoy, Aren (Box 7, Folder 63)
  - Porfer, Sophia Schulner (Box 7, Folder 64)
  - Pritkin, Leonard (Box 7, Folder 65)
  - Rappaport, Schusterow Hedda (Box 7, Folder 66)
  - Radin, Hilda Agawam (Box 7, Folder 67)
  - Raff, Ruth Novack (Box 7, Folder 68)
  - Reivich, Elizabeth Lapida (Box 7, Folder 69)
  - Revzin, Geraldyne (Box 7, Folder 70)
  - Rimm, Sime (Box 7, Folder 71)
  - Robb, Dan & Pauline (Box 7, Folder 72)
  - Rose, Brina (Box 7, Folder 73)
  - Rose, Deborah (Box 7, Folder 74)
  - Rosen, Milton (Box 7, Folder 75)
  - RosenBlum, Alex (Box 7, Folder 76)
  - Roskies, Diane (Box 7, Folder 77)
  - Rosman, Abraham (Box 7, Folder 78)
  - Roth, Chane Drexler FSYA Board Member (Box 7, Folder 79)
  - Roth, Rose (Box 7, Folder 80)
  - Rubin, Roth (Box 7, Folder 81)
  - Miscellaneous Correspondence (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Safadi, Michaela Heller (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Sage, Howard (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Sallen, Molly (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Saliten, Frances (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Salz, Norma (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Doris, Sass (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Schachner, Ruth Rubin (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Schaefer, Lyvia (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Schein, Weiberg Bette (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Schildt, Sylvia Siegel (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Schneider, Bernard (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Schulman, Mary (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Schwartz, Arthur (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Schwartz, Emanuel (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Schwartz, Khayen (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Schweid, Barry (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Shak, Gella Messinger FSYSA Board Member (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Shak Jr (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Shandler, Jeff (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Shapero, Belle FSYSA Board Member (Box 8, Folder 21)
  - Shapero, Leo (Box 8, Folder 22)
  - Shapero, Ray (Box 8, Folder 23)
  - Shaw, [Maeke] (Box 8, Folder 24)
  - Shein, Arturo Kerbel (Box 8, Folder 25)
  - Selden, Tamara Kleinfield (Box 8, Folder 26)
  - Shifrin, Norma (Box 8, Folder 27)
  - Shlosser, Nerkhe (Box 8, Folder 28)
  - Shvetsky, Kate (Box 8, Folder 29)
  - Siegel Tzippy (Box 8, Folder 30)
  - Siff, Helen (Box 8, Folder 31)
  - Silverman, Raissa (Box 8, Folder 32)
  - Simon, Madeline (Box 8, Folder 33)
  - Slutsky, Mendl (Box 8, Folder 34)
  - Smith, Jessi (Box 8, Folder 35)
  - Sokolskey, Esther (Box 8, Folder 36)
  - Sokolskey, Mara Conn (Box 8, Folder 37)
  - Solodar, Betty Mogil (Box 8, Folder 38)
  - Solomon, Leona and Sidney (Box 8, Folder 39)
  - Solomon, Masha (Box 8, Folder 40)
  - Srebrnik, Henry (Box 8, Folder 41)
  - Stein, Ruth (Box 8, Folder 42)
  - Steinberg, Miriam (Box 8, Folder 43)
  - Stern, Pesl Beckler Semel (Box 8, Folder 44)
  - Stonehill, Bob (Box 8, Folder 45)
  - Stonehill, Lee (Box 8, Folder 46)
  - Swerdlow, Amy (Box 8, Folder 47)
  - Switzer, Gail FSYSA Board Member (Box 8, Folder 48)
  - Taube, Herman (Box 8, Folder 49)
  - Taube, Michael (Box 8, Folder 50)
  - Teitelbaum, Perl (Box 8, Folder 51)
  - Thomson, David (Box 8, Folder 52)
  - Timby, Sara (Box 8, Folder 53)
  - Tobin, Phyllis Oppenheim (Box 8, Folder 54)
  - Toplin, Ezra (Box 8, Folder 55)
  - Toplin, Marta (Box 8, Folder 56)
  - Torin, David (Box 8, Folder 57)
  - Tuber, Edith Brensel (Box 8, Folder 58)
  - Turett, Tzivia (Box 8, Folder 59)
  - Turitz, Zitha (Box 8, Folder 60)
  - Vaisman, Y [NC] (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Vanek, Zdenek (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Vectman, Frania (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Vishner, Esther (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Vishner, Ira (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Viswanath, Gitl (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Vogel, Libbe (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Wagner, Sylvia (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Waife, Robert (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - Waletsky (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Wanamaker, Edith/ Bashe (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Weinberg, Mort (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - Weinrauch, Reyzl (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Weinstein, May (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Wesishman Sore (Box 9, Folder 15)
  - Weinman, Janice (Box 9, Folder 16)
  - Weiss, Annabelle Rekoon (Box 9, Folder 17)
  - Weitzel, Sandra (Box 9, Folder 18)
  - Wilner Diana (Box 9, Folder 19)
  - Wiseman [SLM] (Box 9, Folder 20)
  - Wolfthal Diane (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - Wolk, Chic (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - Wolkowicz, Shoshana Balaban (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Yachness, Chane (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Yale, Aaron (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Younin, Sylvia (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Young, Mildred Bogen (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Zeltzer, George (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Zolotarov, Riva (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - Zuckerman, Carol (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Zuckerman, Harold and Dorothy (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - Zurer, Diana Woll (Box 9, Folder 32)
- Series 5: Accession 2017-131
  Scope and Contents
  Boxes 1-3, Bornstein, Paula: Suburban Jewsh school: rituals and life cycle events. Boxes 5-7, Fishman, Gella: Schweid - correspondence.
  - Borenstein, Paula, 1970-1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Borenstein, Paula, 1973-1975 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Borenstein, Paula, 1976-1979 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Borenstein, Paula, 1980-1982 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Borenstein, Paula, 1983-1986 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Borenstein, Paula, 1987-1989 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Borenstein, Paula, 1991-1996 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Borenstein, Paula, 1997-1999 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Borenstein, Paula, 2000-2003 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Borenstein, Paula, 2004-2008 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Borenstein, Paula, 2009-2010 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Borenstein, Paula, 2011-2013 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Borenstein, Paula: duplicates from various years (Box 3)
  - Fishman, Gella: bookplates (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Fishman, Gella: FYSNA fellowship applications, 2001-2006 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Fishman, Gella: FYSNA fellowship applications, 2007-2008 (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Fishman, Gella: FYSNA fellowship - Tony Michels (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Fishman, Gella: FYSNA fellowship - Ester Reiter (Box 5, Frame 5)
  - Fishman, Gella: FYSNA fellowship - Adam J. Sacks (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - general, 1986-2003 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - general, 2005-2007 (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - general, 2008-2010 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Fishman, Gella: interviews - Alfie Fogel, tape 1 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Fishman, Gella: interviews - Alfie Fogel, tape 2 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Fishman, Gella: interviews - list of names (Box 5, Frame 12)
  - Fishman, Gella: interviews - list of tapes (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Fishman, Gella: interviews - Gail Messinger Shak (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Fishman, Gella: interviews - other documents (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - people - Anna Levia (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - people - Khane Roth (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - people - Gail Switzer, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - people - Gail Switzer, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - people - Gail Switzer, 2008 (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - people - Gail Switzer, 2009-2010 (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - people - Dorothy Wachtenheim, 2006 (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - people - Dorothy Wachtenheim, 2007 (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - PR (no date) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - PR, 1955-1999 (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - PR, 2000-2002 (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - PR, 2003 (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - PR, 2004-2006 (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - PR, 2007-2008 (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - PR, 2009-2010 (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - PR - obituaries (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - Yiddish camps - Boiberik (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - Yiddish camps - Kinderland (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Fishman, Gella: correspondence - Yiddish camps - others (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - And Still We Speak: stories of communities sustaining and reclaiming language and culture by Laurie Olsen, 2002 (Box 7)
  - Cassette tapes of interviews (11) (Box 7)
  - Lehman, Naomi: Passover filmstrip and guide (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Lehman, Naomi (donor) (Box 8, Folder 2-6)
  - Exhibit selections (Box 9, Folder 1-4)
  - Yiddish, an introduction to the language, literature and culture, vol. 1 (8 cassettes) (Box 9)
  - Yiddish, language/30, 2 cassette tapes and a phrase dictionary and study guide (Box 9)
  - Israel's story in maps, Ministry of Foreign Affairs, CD (Box 9)
  - Vessel of Song, the music of Mikhl Gelbert, CD (Box 9)
  - Exhibit selections (Box 10, Folder 1-13)
  - Layout of placement of people in photograph in folder 2; list with some names of people in the photograph, 1930-05-23-1930-05-25 (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Large group panoramic photo, black and white., 1930 (Box 11, Folder 2)